RICARDO OLARTE PUELL

(+51) 980-328859 | RAOP155@HOTMAIL.COM

Creative Front-End Developer offering 8+ years of experience providing high-impact solutions for diverse industry organizations. Skilled in developing and testing multiple applications incorporating a range of technologies. Aspiring to combine broad background with strong technical skills to excel as a Front-End Developer. Work well independently and on a team to solve problems, friendly, hardworking, and punctual employee. Experience working with clients in the banking, retail and telecommunications industry.

SKILLS

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Sass, Bootstrap, Bulma
- PHP, MySQL, Vue, jQuery, Git, Electron, ActionScript
- MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PX GROUP S.A. - PERÚ 2012 - Present

Team Lead | Jan 2016 - Present

- Manage development projects from initial design through completion, optimizing all cross-browser and multi-platform compatibility.
- Lead 3 programmers through requirements gathering, design, construction, testing, documentation and implementation of new solutions on time and within budget.
- In charge of research and implementation of new technologies.
- Evaluates the allocation of team resources and tools needed for delivering solutions. Considers impact of new processes on existing processes.
- Creates plans and strategies regarding technical and service solutions to meet current and future business needs.
- Selects, trains, evaluates, supervises, and develops direct reports. Includes development plans and succession plans.
- Establishes relationships and work closely with IT and other external partners to determine and deliver appropriate solutions for the business.
- Reduced queue wait by 80% in "Work Café" Santander Project.

Front-end Developer | Apr 2012 - Dec 2015

- Used a variety of programming languages in order to create user-friendly web apps & desktop apps
- Maintained and improved various web and desktop apps
- Worked in multidisciplinary team with other professionals such as back-end developers and UI/UX designers
- Built high-quality mockups and design different prototypes
- Provided high-quality graphics and visual elements
- Always stayed consistent with our brand guidelines
- Made suggestions for better solutions to problems
- Kept abreast of latest and emerging technologies
- Attended training and educations

IT Assistant | Jan 2012 - Mar 2012

- Installed and configured computer hardware, software, systems, networks, printers and scanners
- Monitored and maintained computer systems and networks
- Responded in a timely manner to service issues and requests
- Repaired and replaced equipment as necessary

EDUCATION

SAN IGNACIO DE LOYOLA'S INSTITUTE Systems Engineer, 2013

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

React-native sin fronteras – *Udemy* 2021

The Complete React Developer Course (w/ Hooks and Redux) – *Udemy 2018*

Master en Frameworks Javascript: Angular, React, Vue - *Udemy* 2018

Front End Libraries - freeCodeCamp 2017

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures - *freeCodeCamp* 2017

Responsive Web Design - freeCodeCamp 2017

LANGUAGES

- Spanish
- English